### Joshua Morse Experienced UX/UI Leader Broomfield, CO

For over 14 years I have used my skills in product design, research, development, analytics, and design team management to improve the experience for users of complex technical products.

I seek opportunities with companies that value their employees' growth and well-being and empower them to tackle complex product design issues.

#### **SKILLS**

#### **User Experience Management**

Agile sprint planning
Contextual interviews & usability testing
Design system creation & maintenance
Employee reviews & mentorship
Flowcharts & sitemaps
Hiring management
Personas, storyboards, & journey maps
Web analytics & KPIs
Wireframes & prototypes

#### Software

Adobe Photoshop & Illustrator Axure RP Google & Heap Analytics Microsoft Office & Google Docs Sketch & InVision

#### **Programming**

HTML/CSS/Sass JavaScript/TypeScript Jekyll & AngularJS

### **CONTACT ME**



opportunities@joshuamorse.com



www.joshuamorse.com



www.linkedin.com/in/jjmorse



www.twitter.com/jjmorse



www.github.com/jjmorse

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# User Experience Manager (remote) RightScale Inc./Flexera (post-acquisition)

February 2013 - Present

- Led the design of top-ranked enterprise products in the 2019 Gartner Cloud Management and 2018 Forester Wave Hybrid Cloud reports.
- Hired, mentored, and managed a team of designers and researchers.
- Worked with product and engineering management to implement Lean practices; organized cross-functional teams to develop new products.
- Oversaw the creation of the RightScale Design System by the UX team.
- Managed web analytics and reporting across the product portfolio.
- Created designs, conducted user research, and wrote front-end code.

# Senior Interaction Designer RightScale Inc.

April 2010 - February 2013

- As the first and only designer at RightScale, I established UX processes and evangelized user-centered design across the company.
- Developed wireframes, personas, flowcharts, sitemaps, & prototypes.
- Oversaw interaction design for RightScale's SaaS and mobile apps.
- Organized a customer advisory group & conducted usability studies.

# Information Architect Enlighten (acquired by Perficient)

May 2008 - April 2010

- Created wireframes, specifications, web prototypes, and user flows.
- Conducted strategic research and performed usability testing.
- Led the effort to update internal UX software tools and processes.
- Clients included Hunter Douglas & Richmond American Homes.

# University Library Associate University of Michigan Graduate Library

August 2006 - May 2008

- Taught faculty and student workshops on a variety of software tools.
- Conducted usability studies with the Library Usability Working Group.
- Competitive position included a full tuition and a living stipend.

#### Software Developer Epic System Corporation

July 2005 - August 2006

- UI and back-end coding for the Beacon Oncology software product.
- · Conducted onsite usability research.

#### **EDUCATION**

# M.S. in Human-Computer Interaction August 2006 - May 2008 University of Michigan School of Information

- Received the top School academic prize, the Margaret Mann Award.
- Second place at the ACM-SIGCHI Student Design Competition.

### B.S. in Computer Science, B.A. in English Hope College

August 2001 - May 2005

- Computer Science & Literature Senior Prizes.
- · National Merit Finalist Scholarship.

### PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

#### **Organizer for the Santa Barbara UX Meetup**

2012 - 2015

- · Speaker for "Web Analytics & User Experience" & "A UX team of One".
- Organized speaking events & coordinated a bi-weekly UX book club.